Bhumika Sharma

Backend Engineer

A Tech-savvy and passionate IT Professional with 7 years of experience in software development using various technologies & frameworks. Ambitious to achieve organizational goals and objectives with my aptitude and expertise. Seeking to have a career in software development with growth potential in technical as well as functional domain to apply my technological skills and knowledge in the best possible way.

bhumikas30@gmail.com



+91-8097210754



Pune, India

in linkedin.com/in/bhumika-sharma-4b07465a

WORK EXPERIENCE

Backend Engineer Redaptive Inc.

07/2021 - present

- Single handedly designed & developed multiple APIs on SAAS platform using Spring boot framework for the web-based proposal model project.
- Implemented the security layer for APIs with Swagger Documentation to be used by the end users.

Sr Software Engineer

HERE Technologies

01/2021 - 07/2021

- Designed & developed software applications for end users to effectively launch and monitor EMR/Spark jobs from front-end automate the process of intimation once the job is completed using Spring boot with HTML, Java, JavaScript & Apache spark.
- Planned, designed & developed data migration logic for 2 heavy loaded legacy HBase tables to AWS cloud, involving ETL processes developed using Apache Spark, AWS Data Pipelines & Scala.
- Single handedly designed & developed reports for the BackSync module for end users using Apache Spark, Scala, ES & Kibana.
- Proposed **cost-effective** solution to avoid scanning a DynamoDB table with sparse indices which ultimately led to better performance of the spark job as well.
- Develop CI/CD Pipelines using Jenkins & Git Lab for automated deployment in Integration/UAT and production environments for multiple projects.

Software Engineer II

HERE Technologies

01/2019 - 01/2021 (2 years)

- Designed & developed a search engine to be used by end users to query details of a place or it's source using Spring Boot frame work with HTML & JavaScript for front end, Elasticsearch as the data store & Java for backend developments.
- Lead and support product development team through the solution strategy and architecture deliverables across the SDLC. Rendered Product Support in Pre-prod and Prod environments.
- Ensure the quality of all deliverables, analyze and interpret business requirements to define and develop technical requirements/specifications and participate in technical design, contributing insights and ideas.

Systems Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services

11/2014 - 12/2018 (4 years)

- Worked with various banks like IDFC, AmBank, Zions etc. to implement SOA for internet banking services for various modules like customer onboarding, Loan creates approve anddisburse etc.
- Served as Systems Engineer and provided input to the software development, analysis and implementation.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Skills: Java 1.8, Scala 2.12 (Basics)
- Frameworks: Spring Boot, Apache Spark (Basics)
- Web Technologies: JavaScript, HTML
- Data Storages: SQL- Oracle, Postgres DB, NoSQL -DynamoDB, Elasticsearch
- Operating Systems: Windows family, Mac OS
- DevOps: Jenkins, Git Lab
- Cloud stack: AWS EC2, CFT, EMR, Dynamo DB, S3, VPC, CloudWatch, Lambda, Billing dashboard, SQS, Athena, Data Pipeline

CERTIFICATES & TRAINING

- Essential training on Elasticsearch by linked in.
- Essential training on Scala by linked in.
- Essential training on AWS & spark by linked in.
- Associate Sun Certified Programmer (SCJP).
- Agile/SCRUM Methodologies.

EDUCATION

B. Tech Computer Science | 73.65% | 2014

Govt Women's Engineering College, Ajmer

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Awarded "Employee of the month" for June 2016 and July 2018 by TCS for dedication and commitment towards the deliveries.
- Awarded Appreciation certificates twice, for special initiatives during the tenure.

LINKS

- Git-Hub Repos
- **Published Tech Blogs**

RECOMMENDATIONS (More Available on request)

- Bhumika is a skilled software engineer focused on qualityoriented deliveries. She is passionate to pursue new technologies to ensure continuous learning and innovation. She has made significant contributions to the projects at HERE Technologies. She exceled under pressure and has demonstrated that she can work on high intensity projects. She is a great team player and willingness to learn quickly and contribute to the success of projects made her a top performer in the team. - Director Of Engineering, HERE Technologies, 2021
- Bhumika is a very strong technical team player who had made valuable contributions in the 2 years I have worked with her in HERE Technologies. She is a guick learner & has a great tenacity to learn & master any given topic or technology. She has a can-do attitude and persistent in resolving technical challenges. She is a great asset and adds strength to the team she is part of. -- Principal Software Engineer, HERE Technologies, 2021.